Guide to the Candace Widmer papers, 1983-1988.
Widmer, Candace papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Candace Widmer papers, 1983-1988.
7858
Widmer, Candace
.3 cubic feet.
Correspondence, reports.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection contains minutes and agendas of the Women's Encampment for a Future of Peace & Justice mailed to Widner from January 1984 through May 1988, logistics for the July 29-August 1, 1983 action and protest, notes and correspondence of the Ithaca Women's Affinity Group, and 2 news stories about the camp (1983, 1984).
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Member of the Ithaca Women's Affinity Group for the Women's Encampment for a Future of Peace & Justice. She lived on Swamp Hill Farm in Ithaca, earned a Ph.D. from Cornell in organizational behavior, and taught for 20 years at Elmira College where she helped create the Women's Studies Program and pass a nondiscrimination policy. She wrote about nonprofit boards and consulted with organizations. In addition to the feminist peace activism reflected in these papers, she worked to make the Ithaca school system responsive to the needs of African-American children and co-founded the Ithaca Cancer Network (ICaN) and the Tompkins County Working Group on Lesbian/Gay/Bisexual/Transgender Aging. She raised 3 children, and her life partner of 25 years was Sue Robinson. She died at age 62 on November 23, 2005.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection contains minutes and agendas of the Women's Encampment for a Future of Peace & Justice mailed to Widner from January 1984 through May 1988, logistics for the July 29-August 1, 1983 action and protest, notes and correspondence of the Ithaca Women's Affinity Group, and 2 news stories about the camp (1983, 1984).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Widmer, Candace.
Subjects:
Antinuclear movement.; Civil disobedience.; Communal living -- United States.; Disarmament.; Feminists.; Land use.; Lesbians.; Nonviolence.; Nuclear disarmament.; Pacifism.; Peace movements -- United States.; Peace; Social action.; Women and peace.; Women's rights.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Similar topics in collection CU 5474, Feminism, pedagogy and the institution of intimacy.
CONTAINER LIST
- Meeting minutes, 1984-01-21 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Meeting minutes, 1984-09-15-1984-09-16 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Meeting minutes, 1985-01-13 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Meeting minutes, 1985-02-02 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Meeting minutes, 1985-10-12 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Meeting minutes, 1985-11-02-1985-11-03 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Meeting minutes, 1985-11-16-1985-11-17 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Meeting minutes, 1986-01 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Includes archives discussion
- Meeting minutes, 1986-02-25 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Meeting minutes, 1986-03 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Meeting minutes, 1986-05-03 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Meeting minutes, 1986-06-18 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Meeting minutes, 1986-07-30 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Meeting minutes, 1986-09-08 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Meeting minutes, 1986-11-20 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Meeting minutes, 1987-05 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Meeting minutes, 1987-11-01 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Meeting minutes, 1987-11-28 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Meeting minutes, 1988-02-13-1988-02-14 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Meeting minutes, 1988-03-19 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Meeting minutes, 1988-05-22 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Logistics for protest, 1983-07-29-1983-08-01 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- News stories, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Ithaca Women's Affinity Group, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Mailings, 1986-04 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Mailing with meeting notes, agenda, 1986-08-26 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Report and health survey with mailings, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 27)